Harshit Kumar

Delhi NCR | E-Mail: hpathak326@gmail.com | Mobile: +91-9910783356 | Skype Id: hpathak326

Career Profile

An MBA graduate with professional work experience of 6 years in Marketing & Business Development function, working for leading technology & event companies.

<u>Core Competencies:</u> Digital and Social Media Marketing, Event Management (Customer and Partner Events), Agency Management, ATL and BTL Campaigns execution Strengths: Strong Interpersonal and communication skills, Analytical skills, Project management skills

Experience

Marketing Associate: Mobility and Storage Business, South West Asia Region Samsung India Electronics Pvt Ltd (Employed through Manpower Group)

April 2018- Present

Marketing: Smartphones and Tablets for Samsung Enterprise Business

- Handle the marketing plan and execution for mobile devices and mobility solutions across industry verticals such as Education, Government, Telecom, Banking, Micro-Finance Institutions, Start-ups and SMBs
- Manage marketing support and communication with Channels/Alliance Partners including Distributors, VARs, ISVs and System Integrators
- Sales support and Sales enablement activities including brochures, leaflets, POSM, Posters, Standees, in shop branding, store branding, retail activation, case studies, videos, use cases etc
- Manage multiple agencies including creative, activation, media and digital to deliver marketing campaigns
- Responsible for launch of all mobility products for enterprises including flagships
- Promoting Samsung's Corporate employee purchase program B2B2C motion (country's largest)
- Responsible for running multiple digital Marketing initiatives: Maintain hygiene of Samsung Enterprise Business website, GDN, Paid Search, Social Media, Content Marketing, Database Marketing, CDM programs, Blogs, Influencer Marketing
- Creative and media management for releasing print ads in national dailies and industry/trade publications
- Industry events participation: Manage Samsung presence in events for CXOs, Government, Education, MFIs

Marketing: Memory Cards and Solid State Drives for Samsung Storage Business

- Digital Promotions with leading retailers, Search, GDN, Website, email, Review marketing, Organic and Inorganic social media campaigns on Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and YouTube
- Channel activation through POSM, Shop-In-Shop, partner events, store brandings, IT hub activations
- Retail activation and branding in LFRs, retail outlets
- Development of training materials for sales team and partners sales
- Industry events participation and management: CIOs, Gamers, Media professionals, other exhibitions

Manager – Global Client Relations Events 4 Sure

Feb 2014 – June 2016 Nov 2016 – April 2018

Product/Event Conceptualization and Strategic Planning:

- Responsible for target based business development from the international legal market: from generation of leads to bringing sponsors & exhibitors on-board
- Identifying & signing up renowned keynote speakers, exhibitors and delegates both for international as well as domestic onsite conferences
- Hosting company's webinar to promote and create brand awareness amongst international legal fraternity
- Planning company's yearly global event schedule: leveraging the past data against current market trends

- Communicating the market opportunities, trends, needs and post event partner feedback to internal crossfunctional teams
- Ensuring a "no surprises" commitment to event sponsors and exhibitors through communication and collaboration
- Regularizing the reports of achievement versus budget forecasts with the senior management team

Key Achievements

- Achieved the highest sales of USD 50K in a month (direct sale of sponsorships, delegate passes and speaking slots) – January 2017
- Managed international client engagement team from London, Dubai, Singapore, and India
- Onsite management of company's mega events in Singapore, London, Thailand and Dubai 2014-17

Education

- MBA (Marketing) IIPM, NEW DELHI in 2014 (Full Time)
- Hotel Management graduate B.Sc. (HMCTT) from Punjab Tech. University in 2010
- Science graduate B.Sc. (Computer Science) from Agra University in 2007
- HSC from CRB Memorial Public School, Mainpuri-12th, CBSE, Science Stream, 2004
- SSC from St. Thomas Convent School, Mainpuri-10th, ICSE, 2002

References: On Request